<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Async]]></title><description><![CDATA[An inclusive web tech meetup based in Brighton, UK]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com</link><generator>metalsmith-feed</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 10:42:28 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://asyncjs.com/feed/atom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Why do we need Kubernetes?]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>In 1768 Voltaire proclaimed “if Kubernetes didn’t exist it would be necessary to invent it” which was impressive as Kubernetes was still some 240 years from being invented. This talks aims to unpick this uncanny prescience by imagining a world where Kubernetes does not exist and investigating how we would solve problems with standardisation and operation of modern applications without it.</p>
<p>No Kubernetes experiences is expected, but an awareness of servers and some JS experience would be helpful</p>
<p>N.B. May contain minor historical inaccuracies.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/kubernetes</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/kubernetes</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/3/39/Kubernetes_logo_without_workmark.svg/1200px-Kubernetes_logo_without_workmark.svg.png</url><title>Kubernetes logo</title><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kubernetes</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Ollie Edwards ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Why Frontend Needs a Standard Server Runtime]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>For frontend developers, it feels like the tools and platforms on offer have never been better. But dig a little deeper, and you&#39;ll see that while things are pretty rosy for statically-hosted apps, there&#39;s a rapid increase in complexity when adding server-side logic or rendering. In this talk, we&#39;ll look at how that manifests, what it means for each of your apps &amp; the open-source landscape at large, and how a new project, Frontend Application Bundles or FABs, can help solve it.</p>
<h3 id="update">Update!</h3>
<p>This meetup now be sponsored by <a href="https://www.homeflow.co.uk/">Homeflow</a>, so beers and pizzas for all! If you have any dietary requirements, please get in touch at hello AT asyncjs DOT com.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/frontend-application-bundles</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/frontend-application-bundles</guid><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/23264/53997173-49745400-418f-11e9-87d0-60a9da6449e6.png</url><title>FAB logo</title><link>https://fab.dev</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Glenn Maddern ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Designing Network Sympathetic Applications]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Network specialist Chris Tomkins&#39; talk will take you through some interesting and non-obvious characteristics of how TCP/IP networks like the Internet work, and how you can design your client-server applications to be &quot;good citizens&quot; and perform well in a variety of suboptimal networking scenarios.</p>
<p>The audience should have a basic understanding of IP addresses, and ideally a bit of knowledge about TCP/IP and building client/server/websockets applications.</p>
<h3 id="lightning-talk">&quot;Lightning&quot; Talk</h3>
<p>I&#39;m happy to announce that Daniel van Berzon will be doing an extended lightning talk at the start of the evening to provide us with the findings from his groundbreaking <a href="https://www.howreadable.com">experiment on code readability</a>.</p>
<h3 id="update">Update!</h3>
<p>This meetup now be sponsored by <a href="https://automattic.com/work-with-us/">Automattic</a>, so beers and pizzas for all! If you have any dietary requirements, please get in touch at hello AT asyncjs DOT com.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/designing-network-sympathetic-applications</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/designing-network-sympathetic-applications</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://live.staticflickr.com/4025/4349850421_321ef83ca3_c_d.jpg</url><title>Filage - Wires (164 / 365)</title><link>https://flickr.com/photos/jfournierphoto/</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Chris Tomkins ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[2019 International Show n' Tell]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>The November migration of the world&#39;s top web developers to the sunny city of Brighton &amp; Hove can only mean one thing - <a href="http://2019.ffconf.org/">FFConf 2019</a> is coming. So, it&#39;s time for another <strong>International Async Show&#39;n&#39;tell</strong>! This year&#39;s instalment will be <em>on Thursday 7th November</em>. The ever popular International show&#39;n&#39;tell is the perfect opportunity to give a peek at your passion project, try out a lightning talk, or just share what&#39;s on your mind.</p>
<p><em>If you’d like to grab a speaking slot</em>, you’ll have five minutes on the night to tell us about something… a project, a library, a technique, a story, or anything else about JavaScript, related tech (HTML, CSS, SVG, etc), or the wider world of web. We hope to bring together a blend of local projects with those from travellers to England for the conference.</p>
<p>Speakers, please <a data-gist href="https://gist.github.com/orangespaceman/196f4e37b2dcd5bee37fe1367bbf2896">add a comment to the Speakers&#39; Gist</a>.</p>
<p>For a spot of inspiration, take a look at our International Show n&#39; Tells in <a href="https://asyncjs.com/international-show-n-tell-2018/">2018</a>, <a href="https://asyncjs.com/international-show-n-tell-2017/">2017</a>, <a href="https://asyncjs.com/international-show-n-tell-2016/">2016</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell-2015/">2015</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell-2014/">2014</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell-2013/">2013</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell-2012/">2012</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/international2011/">2011</a> and <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell3/">2010</a>.</p>
<h3 id="update">Update</h3>
<p>Brandwatch have stepped in at the last moment to offer sponsorship, hooray! (They&#39;re <a href="http://jobs.jobvite.com/careers/brandwatch/job/oZisbfwE?__jvst=Career+Site">hiring</a>). Free beers &amp; pizzas for all. Please contact hello AT asyncjs DOT com if you have specific dietary requirements.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/international-show-n-tell-2019</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/international-show-n-tell-2019</guid><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3289/3060694963_3d778f69dd_z_d.jpg</url><title>The Juggler II</title><link>https://www.flickr.com/photos/helico</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ All and sundry ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Virtual Jungle]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Come along to the Async <a href="https://brightondigitalfestival.co.uk/">BDF</a> Special to help create an immersive augmented-reality jungle scene which you can view directly on your phone&#39;s web browser!</p>
<p>Whether your want to try your hand at creating 3D models of the Jungle&#39;s denizens using Virtual Reality, bring them to life through web technologies such as <a href="https://aframe.io/">A-Frame</a> and <a href="https://github.com/jeromeetienne/AR.js">AR.js</a>, or help craft the arts &amp; crafts jungle background, we could use your skills!</p>
<p>Brighton-based <a href="https://mnemoscene.io">Mnemoscene.io</a> will be on hand to coach us through the use of VR headsets to create models in <a href="https://vr.google.com/blocks/">Google Blocks</a> and view them in <a href="https://www.tiltbrush.com/">Tilt Brush</a> scenes. There will also be an A-Frame workshop to learn how to view your creations using open source &quot;WebXR&quot; technology.</p>
<p>This meetup be sponsored by <a href="https://automattic.com/work-with-us/">Automattic</a>, so beers and pizzas for all! If you have any dietary requirements, please get in touch at hello AT asyncjs DOT com.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/virtual-jungle</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/virtual-jungle</guid><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>/img/talks/virtual_jungle.png</url><title>King of the jungle</title><link>https://poly.google.com/view/0Bvdf1H6zHC</link></image></item><item><title><![CDATA[Editing the world]]></title><description><![CDATA[<h3 id="main-talk">Main Talk</h3>
<p>Ever wondered how to implement editors in the browser? What about repeatable and reversible changes, rich text, syntax highlighting, mixing text with arbitrary content or god forbid - editing recursive data structures as text?</p>
<p>Julian has been obsessing over questions like these for a few years now and is ready to share and discuss his findings. Expect demos, code examples, some talk about design, lots of opinions and maybe even a little fun!</p>
<p>Audience expectations: Intermediate JavaScript knowledge, some familiarity with React would be great too.</p>
<h3 id="lightning-talk">Lightning Talk</h3>
<p>Freya Brown - Writing Bots with JavaScript</p>
<h3 id="update">Update!</h3>
<p>This meetup will now be sponsored by <a href="https://automattic.com/work-with-us/">Automattic</a>, so beers and pizzas for all! If you have any dietary requirements, please get in touch at hello AT asyncjs DOT com.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/editing-the-world</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/editing-the-world</guid><pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://live.staticflickr.com/6160/6198533837_68f9873b4a_z_d.jpg</url><title>Starting to write</title><link>https://www.flickr.com/photos/dmelchordiaz/6198533837/</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Julian Krispel-Samsel ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[The nitty-gitty]]></title><description><![CDATA[<h3 id="main-talk">Main Talk</h3>
<p><a href="https://git-scm.com">Git</a> is not complicated, but it is complex (and confusing). In this talk, Daniel explains the basic building blocks of git: commits, blobs, trees and refs. He then builds on this foundation, past branches and merges to remotes and rebases in an attempt to demystify the tool we all rely on.</p>
<p>Some exposure to git would be beneficial to enjoy this talk</p>
<h3 id="lightning-talk">Lightning Talk</h3>
<p><a href="https://remi-shergold.com/">Remi Shergold</a> will give us a lightning talk on CSS Modules</p>
<h3 id="update">Update</h3>
<p>This meetup will be sponsored by <a href="https://www.creative-technologies.co.uk">Creative Technologies</a>, so beers and pizzas for all! If you have any dietary requirements, please get in touch at hello AT asyncjs DOT com.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/nitty-gitty</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/nitty-gitty</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://git-scm.com/images/logos/downloads/Git-Logo-2Color.png</url><title>Git logo</title><link>https://git-scm.com/downloads/logos</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Daniel van Berzon ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[An introduction to AR.js and A-Frame]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://twitter.com/edsilv">Ed Silverton</a> will be presenting some of the <a href="https://createwebvr.com/webAR.html">WebAR</a> work he has been doing at <a href="http://mnemoscene.io/">Mnemoscene</a>, followed by a coding workshop to introduce some of the basic concepts, including how to use GLTF objects, custom markers, and animation. This workshop is suitable for beginners and experienced web developers with an interest in learning <a href="https://github.com/jeromeetienne/AR.js">AR.js</a> and <a href="https://aframe.io">A-Frame</a>.</p>
<p>You are welcome to <a href="https://www.meetup.com/Async-Web-Tech-Meetup/events/262992187/">sign up for this talk on meetup</a>.</p>
<h2 id="update">Update:</h2>
<p>This meetup will now be sponsored by <a href="https://automattic.com/work-with-us/">Automattic</a>, so beers and pizzas for all! If you have any dietary requirements, please get in touch at hello AT asyncjs DOT com.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/a-frame</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/a-frame</guid><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/9/92/A-Frame_logo.png</url><title>A-Frame logo</title><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A-Frame_(virtual_reality_framework)</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Ed Silverton ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[An Introduction to Gatsby and Gatsby Themes]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>What is <a href="https://www.gatsbyjs.org/">Gatsby</a>? Learn how you can use it to build performant web apps and sites. We’ll cover getting started, sourcing data, and some of Gatsby’s built-in performance optimisations. To finish up we’ll learn about the future of Gatsby with Gatsby Themes.</p>
<p>A basic understanding of <a href="https://reactjs.org/">React.js</a> is assumed.</p>
<p>Sponsored by <a href="https://www.gatsbyjs.org%5D">Gatsby</a> so beers &amp; pizzas for all! If you have any dietary requirements, please get in touch at hello AT asyncjs DOT com.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/gatsby</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/gatsby</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://mutability.netlify.com/Gatsby-Logo.svg</url><title>Gatsby logo</title><link>https://www.gatsbyjs.org/</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Mike Allanson ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Semprola, a semiotic programming language]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Most programming languages are built on ideas that were developed in the 1950s and 1960s and yet a lot about how we use computers has changed since then. Brighton local Oli Sharpe has been researching ideas about how one would build a contemporary programming language given how we use computers today. </p>
<p><a href="https://www.shift-society.org/salon/papers/2018/revised/semprola.pdf">Semprola</a> is the programming language he is developing as a result of this research. The Async talk will first give a brief overview of the thinking behind the ideas of Semprola, a language in which you work with semiotic signs in contexts rather than symbols in text files. Then there will be a brief demo of where Semprola is at today, followed by a short explanation of the way that Javascript is being used to create the (rudimentary!) integrated Semprola IDE.</p>
<p>This won&#39;t be a deep dive into the compiler (or VM!) but the audience will be assumed to have basic understanding of programming.</p>
<p>This meetup will be sponsored by <a href="https://www.creative-technologies.co.uk">Creative Technologies</a>, so beers and pizzas for all! If you have any dietary requirements, please get in touch at hello AT asyncjs DOT com.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/semprola</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/semprola</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://live.staticflickr.com/3931/15415543906_0a9254d3e2_z_d.jpg</url><title>Semiotic architecture</title><link>https://www.flickr.com/photos/enfamous2j/</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Oli Sharpe ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ask the Brains Spring 2019]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>After last year&#39;s successful <a href="https://asyncjs.com/ask-the-brains-spring-18/">Ask the Brains</a> event, we&#39;ll be rebooting it for 2019.</p>
<p>Inspired by the monthly <a href="http://brightonalt.net/">Brighton ALT.NET meetup</a> also hosted at the Skiff, we will be asking/talking/ranting about everything web related - 10 minutes per topic. The aim is to create a friendly environment for everyone to ask their &quot;that thing you&#39;ve never understood but always been too afraid to ask&quot; type questions, plus any other topics you feel like talking about on the night. Topics such as:</p>
<ul>
<li>Should I use Flow JS or TypeScript for my new app? Why?</li>
<li>I&#39;m new to development. Where do I get started?</li>
<li>I still don&#39;t get it! What the hell does &#39;this&#39; mean in Javascript?</li>
<li>How big do I let a project get before using Redux?</li>
<li>What actually is a database index anyway?</li>
<li>What VS Code plugins can you not live without?</li>
<li>Is it just me, or is React Router 5 rubbish?</li>
<li>Should I write unit tests, integration tests, or both?</li>
</ul>
<p>The format works best when there is a diverse group of people and opinions in the room, so whether you consider yourself an absolute beginner, or a seasoned pro, do come and join.</p>
<p>So, please put your thinking caps on now and start thinking of some questions you would like to ask, so you can come prepared!</p>
<h2 id="update">Update</h2>
<p>This meeting will be sponsored by <a href="https://madgex.com/uk/careers#vacancies">Madgex</a>, who will provide pizzas and beers for all. Please get in touch if you have any specific dietary requirements at hello AT asyncjs DOT com.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/ask-the-brains-spring-19</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/ask-the-brains-spring-19</guid><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://live.staticflickr.com/4138/4932655275_9af8d4e8b6_n_d.jpg</url><title>What?</title><link>https://www.flickr.com/photos/debord/</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Everyone ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[React Hooks]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>The highly anticipated feature of React Hooks has finally been released. We can now add state and use side effects in our functional React components.</p>
<p>We are going to take a look at the precursors to Hooks, then learn about how Hooks work and how to use them to improve our React apps.</p>
<p>This meetup will be sponsored by <a href="https://www.creative-technologies.co.uk">Creative Technologies</a>, so beers and pizzas for all! If you have any dietary requirements, please get in touch at hello AT asyncjs DOT com.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/react-hooks</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/react-hooks</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/5/58/Fishing_hooks_on_white_surface.jpg/512px-Fishing_hooks_on_white_surface.jpg</url><title>Fishing hooks on white surface</title><link>https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Fishing_hooks_on_white_surface.jpg</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Matthew McCorry ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Imposter Syndrome]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Imposter syndrome. You may have heard of it. You may have suffered from it. You might not even have realised it at the time.</p>
<p>This talk will explore a journey through imposter syndrome: recognition, acceptance and coping strategies.</p>
<p>Disclaimer: It won&#39;t contain a magic cure, but hopefully some of it will help!</p>
<h3 id="update">Update</h3>
<p>Brandwatch will now be sponsoring! Free beers &amp; pizzas for all. Please contact hello AT asyncjs DOT com if you have specific dietary requirements.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/imposter-syndrome</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/imposter-syndrome</guid><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https:////c1.staticflickr.com/3/2807/9128471890_77a27cc811_h.jpg</url><title>Imposter!</title><link>https://www.flickr.com/photos/42714088@N07/9128471890/</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Pete ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[govuk-react - our UI component library and CI pipeline]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>govuk-react is a React component library for building govuk-styled web applications. We will be giving a demo of its usage, an overview of the technologies used to develop it and show our continuous integration setup including visual regression tests and preview environments.</p>
<p>This will be useful for anyone interested in:</p>
<ul>
<li>automated tests and CI pipelines for UI focussed code</li>
<li>building UI component libraries or design systems</li>
<li>React</li>
</ul>
<p>Alasdair McLeay and Steve Sims are freelance UI developers, currently working on a large public sector project for IBM.</p>
<h3 id="update">Update</h3>
<p>Brandwatch have stepped in at the last moment to offer sponsorship, hooray! Free beers &amp; pizzas for all. Please contact hello AT asyncjs DOT com if you have specific dietary requirements.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/govuk-react</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/govuk-react</guid><pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/a/a7/React-icon.svg/512px-React-icon.svg.png</url><title>React icon</title><link>https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:React-icon.svg</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Alasdair McLeay, Steve Sims ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[WebGL with Dan Neame]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Dan Neame will be kicking off the new Async year with a talk on WebGL. Please note that it&#39;ll be on the <em>second</em> Thursday of the month, to allow us all time recover from our festive hangover! </p>
<p>Dan will be talking about the following topics in ThreeJS:</p>
<ul>
<li>Basics</li>
<li>Geometry</li>
<li>Materials</li>
<li>Postprocessing</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="update">Update</h2>
<p>This meeting will be sponsored by <a href="https://madgex.com/uk/careers#vacancies">Madgex</a>, who will provide pizzas and beers for all. Please get in touch if you have any specific dietary requirements at hello AT asyncjs DOT com.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/webgl</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/webgl</guid><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/2/25/WebGL_Logo.svg</url><title>Khronos Group [Public domain], via Wikimedia Commons</title><link>https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:WebGL_Logo.svg</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Dan Neame ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Useable, Grammatical and Readable code]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>As software developers, we all know that we need to make our code more readable - but how exactly? There is not a lot of literature out there on the subject, and what there is can be very dogmatic and contradictory.</p>
<p>In this talk, Daniel van Berzon attempts to tackle the issue by learning from the worlds of Linguistics and UX, which have successfully solved similar problems. As part of the talk Daniel will present the initial findings from his ongoing readability experiment at <a href="http://howreadable.com">howreadable.com</a>.</p>
<p>Anyone who has written some code, used a website and tried to speak a language (including English) should enjoy this talk.</p>
<h1 id="update">Update:</h1>
<p>This meetup will be sponsored by <a href="https://ocasta.com">Ocasta</a>, so drinks and pizzas for all! This session, all pizzas will be from <a href="http://purezza.co.uk/">Purezza</a>, so no need to let us know dietary requirements except for gluten free as they&#39;ll all be vegan/vegetarian :)</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/readable-code</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/readable-code</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3684/13607959244_bab2160c1a_z_d.jpg</url><title>The Wolf Law Library</title><link>https://www.flickr.com/photos/wolflawlibrary/13607959244</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Daniel van Berzon ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[2018 International Show n' Tell]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>The November migration of the world&#39;s top web developers to the sunny city of Brighton &amp; Hove can only mean one thing - <a href="http://2018.ffconf.org/">FFConf 2018</a> is coming. So, it&#39;s time for another <strong>International Async Show&#39;n&#39;tell</strong>! This year&#39;s instalment will be <em>on Wednesday 7th November</em> - not Thursday. The ever popular International show&#39;n&#39;tell is the perfect opportunity to give a peek at your passion project, try out a lightning talk, or just share what&#39;s on your mind.</p>
<p><em>If you’d like to grab a speaking slot</em>, you’ll have five minutes on the night to tell us about something… a project, a library, a technique, a story, or anything else about JavaScript, related tech (HTML, CSS, SVG, etc), or the wider world of web. We hope to bring together a blend of local projects with those from travellers to England for the conference.</p>
<p>Speakers, please <a data-gist href="https://gist.github.com/larister/ab84a296acf8f6cc51e242ea40dd53ac">add a comment to the Speakers&#39; Gist</a>.</p>
<p>For a spot of inspiration, take a look at our International Show n&#39; Tells in <a href="https://asyncjs.com/international-show-n-tell-2017/">2017</a>, <a href="https://asyncjs.com/international-show-n-tell-2016/">2016</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell-2015/">2015</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell-2014/">2014</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell-2013/">2013</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell-2012/">2012</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/international2011/">2011</a> and <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell3/">2010</a>.</p>
<h2 id="important-notice">Important Notice:</h2>
<p>For the Show&#39;n&#39;Tell we&#39;ll be back in our old venue of <a href="http://68middle.st">68 Middle St</a>, <em>not</em> The Skiff</p>
<h1 id="update">Update:</h1>
<p>This meetup will be sponsored by <a href="https://ocasta.com">Ocasta</a>, so drinks and pizzas for all! This session, all pizzas will be from <a href="http://purezza.co.uk/">Purezza</a>, so no need to let us know dietary requirements except for gluten free as they&#39;ll all be vegan/vegetarian :)</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/international-show-n-tell-2018</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/international-show-n-tell-2018</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3289/3060694963_3d778f69dd_z_d.jpg</url><title>The Juggler II</title><link>https://www.flickr.com/photos/helico</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ All and sundry ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Supercharged Spreadsheets]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>We all know the struggle, when a feature request sounds like the perfect job for a spreadsheet. But... there&#39;s always a tiny detail that makes us believe it&#39;s not quite enough to do the job. Or is it? In this talk, Tibor Besze will demonstrate how to utilise Google Apps Scripts (and a wide variety of Google services and APIs) to get the most out of your Google Sheets. The talk is aimed at Javascript developers of all skill levels, and includes a live demonstration.</p>
<h2 id="update">UPDATE:</h2>
<p>This meetup will now be sponsored by <a href="http://www.brandwatch.com">Brandwatch</a>, so beers and pizzas for all! If you have any dietary requirements, please get in touch at <a href="mailto:hello@asyncjs.com">hello@asyncjs.com</a></p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/supercharged-spreadsheets</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/supercharged-spreadsheets</guid><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://miro.medium.com/max/1054/1*u-AcMWWeLrVVs7gj0QyBOQ.png</url><title>Google Sheets logo</title><link>https://chatbotsmagazine.com/build-a-bot-with-zero-coding-on-google-sheets-922f20d80c51</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Tibor Besze ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Double bill - Electron and Unit Testing]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>October will see the return of the famed Async &quot;Double Bills&quot;.</p>
<p>Part 1: Testing JavaScript by Mark Everitt</p>
<p>A whistle-stop tour of why, what, when, and how to test. This talk should be relevant to all JS coders, from those just starting out to seasoned developers.</p>
<p>Part 2: Electron.js by Dan Neame</p>
<p>Electron allows you to package your web apps as executable Desktop applications. In this talk Dan Neame will cover how Electron works, how to get started with the framework, how to build a complicated application, and how to package these for release across Windows, Linux and Mac.</p>
<h2 id="update">Update</h2>
<p>This meeting will be sponsored by <a href="https://rakutenmarketing.com/en-uk/career/full-stack-engineer">Rakuten Marketing</a>, who will provide pizzas and beers for all. Please get in touch if you have any specific dietary requirements at hello AT asyncjs DOT com.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/double-bill-electron-n-unit-testing</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/double-bill-electron-n-unit-testing</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1873/29163684827_51640f9e0d_z_d.jpg</url><title>Double rainbow</title><link>https://www.flickr.com/photos/snowpeak/</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Dan Neame, Mark Everitt ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Compression]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I&#39;ve always been amazed about how compression formats and algorithms work. Over the past couple of years, I have created a game that features a hand-rolled compression algorithm for the game maps. These consist of two 2D arrays of numbers, corresponding to the game tiles. However, this format can be applied to an integer array of any number of dimensions.</p>
<p>This talk will be about how the compression algorithm works, including condensing the information and then translating to binary, before finally writing to disk.</p>
<h2 id="update">UPDATE:</h2>
<p>This meetup will again be sponsored by the good folk at <a href="http://www.prodpad.com/about-us/jobs/">ProdPad</a>, so beers and pizzas for all! If you have any dietary requirements, please get in touch at <a href="mailto:hello@asyncjs.com">hello@asyncjs.com</a></p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/compression</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/compression</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4079/4785420782_4196588df4_z_d.jpg</url><title>M113 - Car Crusher 2</title><link>https://www.flickr.com/photos/tncountryfan/4785420782</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Niall Coleman ]]</author></item></channel></rss>